the advent of big data and cloud computing
means that we have enormous amounts of data
at our disposal many of these rich data
sets are available for free on the internet
using cloud services such as google bigquery you
can easily access data on all kinds of topics
including things like weather demographics
geospatial and medical data just to name a
few in the past unlocking value from these
data sets required you to have a high degree
of skill in writing code or complex queries
however with new tools like cloud data prep
it is easier than ever before to wrangle this data
and get the insights you need today's 10 minute
challenge is to gather a list of restaurants
pharmacies and banks in your neighborhood
you must collect the names addresses and phone
numbers of these amenities into a spreadsheet
can you do it well the clock is ticking so let's
go you can begin by following the github link in
the video description below the first step is to
go to openstreetmap.org open this up in a new tab
and here enter the address that
you want to center the search on
for this demo i'm going to type
in times square in new york
and once you find the location click on
it and select the little information icon
this will reveal the latitude and longitude
of the location copy this to your clipboard
go back to the github page
and open up the spreadsheet
make a copy of this spreadsheet into your
google drive now go to clouddataprep.com
if you are going here for the first time you
will need to set up your google cloud project
once you are in the main user interface
go to the flows pane and this is where
we will import the flow the flow
can be found on the github page
download this to your local machine
and upload it into cloud data prep
add an output to the recipe and in the output
options we will select a publishing action
add a publishing action for bigquery
choose the default schema
and create a new table this
will be a parameterized table
and we will insert a parameter to represent the
we will have a variable to represent the
amenity and we will give it a default value of
restaurant
you can now run a job for each amenity we
begin with the first one which is restaurant
you can specify the distance
in meters from the center
and also enter the latitude and longitude
that we got from openstreetmaps earlier
and i'm also going to select the type of server in
this case we will pick n1 standard 4 and run this
repeat this for each amenity
so we did just restaurants
the next one would be bank and pharmacy
you can run multiple jobs in parallel
while the job is running in the background let
me quickly show you what the flow looks like
it consists of a data set object which points to
open street maps this is built off of a custom
sql statement which has parameters built in for
longitude latitude and distance in meters if
you look at the recipe itself it has a few steps
the first few steps actually convert the data to
tabular format then it applies filters on the
specific amenity that we enter as a parameter
and then finally we format the column
names and make it suitable for bigquery
at this point all the jobs have finished
executing you can go to google sheets
and add a data connector for each of the
tables in bigquery that you just created
if you followed all the steps you now have a
handy spreadsheet with a list of restaurants
banks and pharmacies near your home pretty useful
if you ask me congratulations on completing the
10 minute challenge if you enjoyed this
video please give it a thumbs up and be
sure to subscribe to the trifacta channel for
more awesome videos thank you for watching